Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
It's like a graveyard.
No heat sources or radar waves detected.
There are no signs of repairs.
They're just drifting lifelessly.
Maybe that's all they're capable of.
They can destroy, but can't repair or create.
So, what's the plan ?
It's too risky to wait here
until the rescue fleet arrives.
The Yamato can transport the refugees to Earth.
That's what we should do, but...
That'll disrupt the schedule.
There's another option.
1800 light years from here in the direction of Telezart...
Planet Stravase...
A Garmillas fleet bound for Earth
will pass near this planet tomorrow.
Ask the fleet to transport the refugees to Earth ?
It's on a routine trip from Garmillas
to Earth with no immediate concerns.
If we explain the situation they
should agree to rendezvous with us.
Telezart is asking for help.
The Yamato should move forward.
More than 200 people were saved,
but ten times that were killed...
...whether they were elders or children.
That's who our enemy is, and you let them go.
I don't know what kind of promise
you made on Iscandar, but...
...I want you to remember what I just said.
Welcome back, Professor.
He said it's on a routine
trip from Garmillas to Earth.
Planet Stravase is the place.
Alright. I want to confirm
the chart on the main bridge.
Okay.
Ah, I'm sor...
It's all yours.
Kodai...?
Doctor !
Kodai looks upset.
Doctor Sado !
Please don't talk so loudly in the sick bay.
Identify yourself.
Mori Yuki of the Earth Defense Force Central Command.
You weren't on the crew manifest.
Well, I just forgot to register...
I can't maintain military discipline like this.
You need to leave the ship.
Alright. I'll leave the ship.
Oh c'mon, both of you...
Doctor, you don't have time. Here.
It's my fault, okay ?
Fighting's no good.
All hands, departure is scheduled at 11:30.
Personnel from each operation department must
confirm your assigned civilian section by 09:00.
W...what are you doing ?
I'm leaving the ship just like you ordered.
What are you talking about ?
How are you going to get back to Earth from here ?
You're the one who told me to leave the ship.
I'll space-walk or whatever to get home.
Lieutenant Mori, I have an order for you.
Doctor Sado.
What is it ?
I feel like Okita is still on the ship.
Yes, he's with everyone.
But they're all young.
They need an adult who can support them.
Well, take care.
I'm just a loser.
You're a wreck.
You're looking tense from every angle.
You'll stress yourself out.
It's none of your business.
Hey Kodai, when the SOS came
from Telezart, we all saw a vision.
Show your resolve.
If we didn't see it, do you think everyone
would have gotten on board the Yamato ?
You blew your cover ?
Sorry for all the trouble you
guys went through to hide me.
No worries.
The bond among the Yamato's female crew is strong.
But why ?
I wanted to breathe the air outside.
Besides...
There's a limit to things.
You mean Kodai ?
I guess it's me.
I know I'm no use even if I'm not hiding,
but I don't want to be a burden.
If he tells me to go home, I will, but before that...
...I wanted to tell him I'm here.
I'm envious.
Mori wasn't called by Telezart,
but she still came aboard anyway.
Why do you think she did that ?
You knew ?!
Be true to yourself. It's not
shameful to depend on someone.
You can bring up military discipline
all you want, but this is the Yamato.
I'll look the other way, at least.
Yamato...
Damn you, Yamato...
What's wrong with me ?
What is this irrational rage ?
Yamato...Yamato...
200 million km to Stravase.
Mori Yuki reporting.
As soon as we arrive at Stravase, the Deputy Commander will board the Garmillas ship for the final arrangements.
If there are no problems,
we'll begin the transfer immediately.
The civilians and Space Cavalry members will be split up
between the three Garmillas ships and head back to Earth.
Once again, I'm assigning you to escort duty.
Order acknowledged.
We'll be transferred to a
Garmillas ship on that planet, right ?
Even though the Garmillans
are with us, are we really safe ?
I understand how you feel.
But, I'll be with you.
Don't worry.
We'll be with you, too.
Let's set foot on the
Earth's surface together, okay ?
If you're with us, Commander...
That'll be a relief.
Thank you so much.
I have to hurry back, though...
Our commander believes that
vengeance is all that's left in his life.
Umm, Mr. Saito...
A responsible and attractive woman.
That's it.
Those are the ruins of Stravase that
I've heard about from the Garmillans.
If we could study it, we might be able to solve
the mystery of the ancient Archelias civilization.
Even so...
Professor.
You'll have to create that opportunity yourself.
The Garmillas fleet is approaching
the rendezvous point on time.
Please don't push.
We have plenty of time.
You're a lifesaver.
We wish we could take our
people back home ourselves, but...
You can count on us.
Besides, Telezart is one of our biggest mysteries.
I'm looking forward to what the Yamato discovers.
Oh, Lieutenant Keyman...
About a substitute correspondent to take your post...
I'll return to the ship.
Thank you, Deputy Commander.
We're sorry for letting you take on a duty like this.
That's unimportant.
Have you obtained “it” ?
Yes, sir.
I never imagined your original plan of bringing the Yamato to us would come true this way.
It must be because of your blessed lineage.
That's irrelevant.
Things tend to happen unexpectedly.
Open it.
This is exactly what you asked for.
It can control or even destroy
the Yamato's wave motion engine.
Anti-wave motion photon...
Please stay in line so you don't get hurt.
Hey.
Ma'am !
Are you getting on the ship, too ?
I am.
Can we meet again once we get to Earth ?
Sure.
It's a bit heavy, but we
can talk anytime with this.
We can stay in contact with each other,
even between two different ships.
It's better than asking Garmillas to borrow a communication device every time, isn't it ?
Thank you.
But is it okay for me to
use equipment like this ?
My commander insisted.
Goodbye over a cup of sake ?
I don't understand why we
have to say goodbye, though...
The current Yamato has no fangs.
It doesn't have the spirit to fight our enemy.
So I'll return to Earth and ask to be
assigned to a ship with the spirit to fight.
Don't you feel the same way ?
This is the ship my best friend risked his life for.
Let me see it out until my last moment.
It's about time for the refugees to depart.
Someone representing the Yamato...
...should probably hear a word or two.
Like, maybe from the Acting Captain.
Got it.
Let's go.
Yuki...
The Professor...
That's Professor Redrowz.
The ruins ?
A civilian went off to the ruins ?
I'll bring him back.
Please take care of the ship, Mr. Sanada.
Such a problem at a time like this...
What is this place ?
Why did the Professor come here ?
Objects emerging from the gas clouds in orbit.
It's a fleet.
What ?
Ships identified.
They're Garmillas ships.
Garmillas ?
So many...
What's the meaning of this, Keyman ?
Missiles approaching rapidly.
What ?
Dead end ?
Professor Redrowz, where are you ?
Acting Captain, this is the Yamato !
We're under attack from enemy ships !
Watch out !
Commander !
Run !
Get to the Garmillas ship now !
Let's get back to the Yamato !
Destructive Liberation Army...?
They're Garmillas political criminals
who have rebelled against the home planet.
We had some skirmishes elsewhere, but I didn't expect them to appear on our route to Earth.
Desler's dead, but his hegemony
still haunts Garmillas to this day.
The planets overrun by Garmillas must be set free.
Now is the time to punish the rotten dictator.
They're coming after us, but we can't move until we finish accommodating the civilians.
We need your help, Yamato.
That's...
You're the only one we can depend on.
We have no choice but to face the fire ?
The Yamato's preparing to take off.
Good, otherwise it was pointless
to lure a real rebel force here.
The Yamato will show some
weakness during the confusion.
The rest is up to "him".
All hands, prepare for emergency take off !
I only have one chance at this
when the wave motion engine starts.
Have we heard from the Acting Captain yet ?
No, no response yet.
Search plane signal confirmed.
They're back ?
As soon as they land, we'll take off.
Engine room, activate the flywheel.
Once it stops shaking, run.
Yamato...
Not there ?
What do you mean by that ?
A civilian piloted it alone.
No, no one else.
Kodai, where are you ?
Archelias. The ancient Archelians
are the origin of all humanity.
Why did you send your people to
so many corners of the galaxy ?
To nurture your successors
upon the end of your civilization ?
If so, why did you have to
maintain the form of a human ?
Professor...
Even though that form brought you death.
It's an irrational life form which can't
reproduce without mating male and female.
Steal, hate, kill...
Humans are the chaos that
disrupts the harmony of the galaxy.
I've been waiting for you.
Who are you ?
My name is Zorder...
...he who knows what love is...
...more than anyone in the universe.
Episode 8
Trap on the Planet Stravase !
Kienai de aoi tsuki yo
Blue moon, please don't fade away
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Saijo Miki:
Hirata Hajime:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Moriya Satomi
Ise Fumihide
Hirata Daisuke
Terashidasu kimi hitohira
It lights up my love just enough
Yamamoto Akira:
Saeki Koji:
Shinoda Koto:
Saito Hajime:
Shiori Nagakura:
Amagi Toshiro:
Okita Juzo:
Hijikata Ryu:
Robert Redrowz:
Katsuragi Touko:
Keyman:
Karzet:
Zorder:
Maser:
Iry:
Monk:
Skipper:
Refugee:
Tanaka Rie
Itatori Masaaki
Hara Yumi
Hiroki Tochi
Amagai Kazusa
Saito Jiro
Sugao Takayuki
Ishizuka Unsho
Hashi Takaya
Kaida Yuko
Kamiya Hiroshi
Onozuka Takashi
Tezuka Hideaki
Kiyama Shigeo
Aoki Shiki
Sawaki Ikuya
Fujinuma Kento
Nokubi Naoko
Nani hitotsu kawaranai
Everything was routine
Monotone iro no hibi
Monotone days for so long
Unmei ga tsurete kita
Fate brought you to me
Kimi no me ni koi wo shita
I fell in love with your eyes
Chikaku ni kanjitai yo
I want to feel you close
Atatakai te ni furete
Touching your warm hands
Aa sugu ni kotoba ni dekitara
Wishing I could put this into words right away
Konnani ai shiteru
I love you so much
Kakurenai de koigokoro yo
Loving feelings, please don't hide
Kimi dake terashiteru yo
It sheds light only on you
Konya nara sou ieru
I can say that because tonight is different
Preview
Emergency ascent !
The Yamato will act as a decoy !
I'll show you what your love will allow to live and die.
Kodai...
Yuki !
Episode 09
Zorder's Demonic Choice